Please enable Javascript in your browser.

* Menu

Our Policies
============

* * *

Terms of ServicePrivacy PolicyCookie NoticeReviews PolicyReturn PolicyDE&I InitiativesAuthorized Reseller PolicyEditorial PolicyAccessibility

Privacy Policy

Terms of Service

Privacy Policy

Cookie Notice

Reviews Policy

Return Policy

DE&I Initiatives

Authorized Reseller Policy

Editorial Policy

Accessibility

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective as of March 28, 2023

This Privacy Policy describes how Natals, Inc. (**"Ritual", "we", "us" or "our"**) handles personal information that we collect through our digital properties that link to this Privacy Policy, including our website [https://ritual.com](https://ritual.com/) ("**Site**"), as well as through social media, our marketing activities, our live events, and other activities described in this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "**Services**").

**UNITED KINGDOM USERS**: Please see the Notice to UK users section below for additional information for individuals located in the United Kingdom ("**UK**").

**California Notice at Collection**: See the [State Privacy Rights Notice below](#state-privacy-rights-notice) for important information about your rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act.

### Personal information we collect

**Information you provide to us**. Personal information you may provide to us through the Services includes:

* **Contact data**, such as your first and last name, salutation, email address, billing and mailing addresses, and phone number.
    
* **Profile data**, such as the username and password that you may set to establish an online account on the Site, and any other information that you add to your account profile.
    
* **Pregnancy-related data**, such as due date and pregnancy status (whether you are trying, not trying, expecting or just had a baby).
    
* **Communications data**, based on our exchanges with you, including when you contact us through the Site, social media, or otherwise.
    
* **Transactional data**, such as information relating to or needed to complete your orders on or through the Site, including order numbers and transaction history.
    
* **Marketing data**, such as your preferences for receiving our marketing communications and details about your engagement with them.
    
* **Payment data** needed to complete transactions, including payment card information or bank account number.
    
* **Promotion data**, including information you share when you enter a competition, promotion, or complete a survey. Please note that if you participate in a sweepstakes, contest, or giveaway through the Service, we may ask you for your contact data to notify you if you win, to verify your identity, and/or to send you prizes. In some situations, we may need additional information as a part of the entry process, such as a prize selection choice. These sweepstakes and contests are voluntary. We recommend that you read the rules and other relevant information for each sweepstakes and contest that you enter.

**Third-party sources**. We may combine personal information we receive from you with personal information we obtain from other sources, such as:

* **Public sources**, such as government agencies, public records, social media platforms, and other publicly available sources.
    
* **Private sources**, such as data providers, social media platforms, and data licensors.
    
* **Our affiliate partners**, such as our affiliate network provider and publishers, influencers, and promoters who participate in our paid affiliate programs.
    
* **Marketing partners**, such as joint marketing partners and event co-sponsors.
    
* **Third-party services** (such as Apple or Google) that you use to log into, or otherwise link to, your Ritual account. This data may include your username, profile picture, and other information associated with your account on that third-party service that is made available to us based on your account settings on that service.

**Automatic data collection**. We, our service providers, and our business partners may automatically log information about you, your computer or mobile device, and your interaction over time with the Site, our communications, and other online services, such as:

* **Device data**, such as your computer or mobile device's operating system type and version, manufacturer and model, browser type, screen resolution, RAM and disk size, CPU usage, device type (e.g., phone, tablet), IP address, unique identifiers (including identifiers used for advertising purposes), language settings, mobile device carrier, radio/network information (e.g., Wi-Fi, LTE, 3G), and general location information such as city, state or geographic area.
    
* **Online activity data**, such as pages or screens you viewed, how long you spent on a page or screen, the website you visited before browsing to the Site, navigation paths between pages or screens, information about your activity on a page or screen, access times and duration of access, and whether you have opened our emails or clicked links within them.

**Cookies and similar technologies**. Some of our automatic data collection is facilitated by the following technologies.

* **Cookies**, which are small text files that websites store on user devices and that allow web servers to record users' web browsing activities and remember their submissions, preferences, and login status as they navigate a site. Cookies used on our sites include both "session cookies" that are deleted when a session ends, "persistent cookies" that remain longer, "first party" cookies that we place (used to recognize your computer or mobile device when it revisits our Sites and to store certain information from your current session to deliver a more personalized shopping experience) and "third party" cookies that our third-party business partners and service providers place.
    
* **Local storage technologies**, like HTML5, that provide cookie-equivalent functionality but can store larger amounts of data on your device outside of your browser in connection with specific applications.
    
* **Web beacons**, also known as pixel tags or clear GIFs, which are used to demonstrate that a webpage or email was accessed or opened, or that certain content was viewed or clicked.
    
* **Session-replay technologies**, such as those provided by FullStory, that employ software code to record users' interactions with the Services in a manner that allows us to watch and analyze visual reconstructions of those user sessions. The replays may include users' clicks, mobile app touches, mouse movements, scrolls, and keystrokes/key touches during those sessions. These replays help us diagnose usability problems and identify areas for improvement. You can learn more about FullStory at [https://www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy-policy) and you can opt-out of session recording by FullStory at [https://www.fullstory.com/optout/](https://www.fullstory.com/optout/).
    
* **Chat technologies**, such as those provided by Intercom, that employ cookies and software code to operate the chat features that you can use to communicate with us through the Service. We and such third-party providers may access and use information about webpages visited on our website, your IP address, your general geographic information (e.g., city, state), and other personal information you share through online chats for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

For more information, see our [Cookie Notice](https://ritual.com/cookie-notice). We will store a record of your preferences with respect to the use of those technologies in connection with the Site.

**Data about others**. We may offer features that help users invite their friends or contacts to use the Service, and we may collect contact details about these invitees so we can deliver their invitations. Please do not refer someone to us or share their contact details with us unless you have their permission to do so.

### How we use your personal information

We may use your personal information for the following purposes:

**Service delivery**, which may include using your personal information to:

* provide and operate the Service
    
* establish and maintain your Ritual user profile
    
* remember devices from which you have previously logged in
    
* discern whether you are logged in when you visit password-protected areas of the Site
    
* provide support for the Service, and respond to your requests, questions, and feedback
    
* communicate with you about the Service, including by sending Service-related announcements, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Profile data
        
    * Communications data
        
    * Transactional data
        
    * Payment data

**Security**, which may include using your personal information to:

* enable security features of the Service, such as by sending you security codes via email or SMS
    
* remember devices from which you have previously logged in
    
* communicate with you about the Service, including by sending Service-related announcements, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Device data
        
    * Online activity data

**Service personalization**, which may include using your personal information to:

* understand your needs and interests
    
* personalize your experience with the Service and our Service-related communications
    
* remember your selections and preferences as you navigate the Site
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Profile data
        
    * Pregnancy-related data
        
    * Device data
        
    * Online activity data

**Direct marketing**, which may include using your personal information to:

* send you direct marketing communications (you may opt-out of our marketing communications as described in the Opt-out of marketing section below)
    
* personalize our marketing communications according to your needs and interests
    
* monitor your interaction with our communications (such as whether you opened them)
    
* facilitate your invitations to friends who you want to invite to join the Service
    
* Categories of personal information involved
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Profile data
        
    * Communications data
        
    * Transactional data
        
    * Marketing data

**Interest-based advertising**, which may include using your personal information to:

* share aggregated, de-identified, or otherwise anonymized data with third parties, including to promote our business through interest-based advertising on third party channels
    
* share information about our users with our third-party advertising partners to facilitate interest-based advertising to those or similar users on other online platforms
    
* allow our third-party advertising partners to collect information about your interaction with the Site, our communications, and other online services over time and use that information to serve online ads that they think will interest you
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Device data
        
    * Online activity data

**SMS Marketing and Support**, which may include using your personal information to:

* send you text notifications for your order (including abandoned checkout reminders), text marketing offers, transactional texts, and requests for reviews. We use information stored in a cookie to save information about your cart for future use and determine whether it has been abandoned.
    
* share opt-in data with our messaging partners and service providers, for the sole purpose of enabling and operating our text messaging program
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Transactional data
        
    * Marketing data

**Promotions and contests**, which may include using your personal information to:

* administer promotions and contests
    
* communicate with you about promotions or contests in which you participate
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Promotion data
        
    * Contact data
        
    * Profile Data
        
    * Communications data

**Service analytics**, which may include using your personal information to:

* analyze your usage of the Service in an aggregated, de-identified, and/or anonymized form
    
* improve the Service
    
* improve the rest of our business
    
* help us understand user activity on the Service, including which pages are most and least visited and how visitors move around the Service, as well as user interactions with our emails. For more information, see our [Cookie Notice](https://ritual.com/cookie-notice).
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Device data
        
    * Online activity data

**Compliance with law and co-operation with authorities**, which may include using your personal information to:

* comply with applicable laws, lawful requests, and legal process, such as to respond to subpoenas or requests from government authorities
    
* audit our internal processes for compliance with legal and contractual requirements or our internal policies
    
* prevent, identify, investigate, and deter fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical, or illegal activity, including cyberattacks and identity theft
    
* cooperate with law enforcement authorities in investigating and prosecuting users who violate our rules or engage in behavior that is illegal or harmful to other users, including suspected fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Any and all data types relevant in the circumstances

**Protection and enforcement of rights**, which may include using your personal information to:

* protect our, your, or others' rights, privacy, safety or property (including by making and defending legal claims)
    
* enforce the terms and conditions that govern the Service and/or Site
    
* prevent, identify, investigate, and deter fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical, or illegal activity, including cyberattacks and identity theft
    
* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Any and all data types relevant in the circumstances

**Data sharing in the context of corporate events**, we may share certain personal information in the context of actual or prospective corporate events – for more information, see How we share your personal information below.

* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Any and all data types relevant in the circumstances

**To create aggregated, de-identified and/or anonymized data** from your personal information by removing information that makes the data identifiable to you. We may use this aggregated, de-identified and/or anonymized data and share it with third parties for our lawful business purposes, including to analyze and improve the Service and promote our business.

* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Any and all data types relevant in the circumstances

**Further uses**, in some cases, we may use your personal information for further uses, in which case we will ask for your consent.

* _Categories of personal information involved_
    
    * Any and all data types relevant in the circumstances

### How we share your personal information

We may share your personal information with the following parties and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection.

**Affiliates**. Our corporate parent, subsidiaries, and affiliates, for their use consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Service providers**. Third parties that provide services on our behalf or help us operate the Service or our business (such as hosting, information technology, customer support, email delivery, marketing, consumer research and website analytics).

**Payment processors**. Any payment card information you use to make a purchase on the Service is collected and processed directly by our payment processors, such as Stripe or PayPal, who may use your payment data in accordance with their privacy policies. Their privacy policies may be found at [https://stripe.com/privacy](https://stripe.com/privacy) (for Stripe) and [https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)(for PayPal).

**Advertising partners**. Third-party advertising companies for the interest-based advertising purposes described above.

**Third parties designated by you**. We may share your personal information with third parties where you have instructed us or provided your consent to do so.

**Business and marketing partners**. Third parties with whom we co-sponsor events or promotions, with whom we jointly offer products or services, or whose products or services may be of interest to you.

**Linked third-party services**. If you log into the Service with, or otherwise link your Service account to, a social media or other third-party service, we may share your personal information with that third-party service. The third party's use of the shared information will be governed by its privacy policy and the settings associated with your account with the third-party service.

**Professional advisors**. Professional advisors, such as lawyers, auditors, bankers and insurers, where necessary in the course of the professional services that they render to us.

**Authorities and others**. Law enforcement, government authorities, and private parties, as we believe in good faith to be necessary or appropriate for the compliance and protection purposes described above.

**Parties to corporate events**. We may disclose personal information in the context of actual or prospective corporate events (e.g., investments in Ritual, financing of Ritual, or the sale, transfer or merger of all or part of our business, assets or shares), for example, we may need to share certain personal information with prospective counterparties and their advisers. We may also disclose your personal information to an acquirer, successor, or assignee of Ritual as part of any merger, acquisition, sale of assets, or similar transaction, and/or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which personal information is transferred to one or more third parties as one of our business assets.

### Your choices

In this section, we describe the rights and choices available to all users. Users who are located in certain [U.S. states](#state-privacy-rights-notice), [Canada](#notice-to-canadian-residents), and the [United Kingdom](#notice-to-uk-users) can find additional information about their rights below.

**Access or update your information**. If you have registered for an account with us through the Site, you may review and update certain account information by logging into the account.

**Opt-out of marketing communications**. You may opt-out of marketing-related emails by following the opt-out or unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of the email, or by contacting us. Please note that if you choose to opt-out of marketing-related emails, you may continue to receive service-related and other non-marketing emails.

**Cookies**. For information about cookies employed by the Service and how to control them, see our Cookie Notice.

**Do Not Track.** Some Internet browsers may be configured to send "Do Not Track" signals to the online services that you visit. We currently do not respond to "Do Not Track" signals. To find out more about "Do Not Track," please visit [https://www.allaboutdnt.com](https://www.allaboutdnt.com/). We respond to the Global Privacy Control signal for California residents, as described further in the [State Privacy Rights Notice](#state-privacy-rights-notice).

**Declining to provide information**. We need to collect personal information to provide certain services. If you do not provide the information we identify as required or mandatory, we may not be able to provide those services.

**Linked third-party platforms**. If you choose to connect to the Service through your social media account or other third-party platform, you may be able to use your settings in your account with that platform to limit the information we receive from it. If you revoke our ability to access information from a third-party platform, that choice will not apply to information that we have already received from that third party.

**Delete your content or close your account**. You can choose to delete certain content through your account. If you wish to request to close your account, please contact us.

### Other sites and services

The Service may contain links to websites, mobile applications, and other online services operated by third parties. In addition, our content may be integrated into web pages or other online services that are not associated with us. These links and integrations are not an endorsement of, or representation that we are affiliated with, any third party. We do not control websites, mobile applications, or online services operated by third parties, and we are not responsible for their actions. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of the other websites, mobile applications, and online services you use.

### Security

We employ a number of technical, organizational, and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information we collect. However, security risk is inherent in all internet and information technologies and we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information.

### International data transfer

We are headquartered in the United States and may use service providers that operate in other countries. Your personal information may be transferred to the United States or other locations where privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your state, province, or country.

Users in the UK should read the important information provided below about transfer of personal information outside of the UK.

### Children

The Service is not intended for use by anyone under 18 years of age. If you are a parent or guardian of a child from whom you believe we have collected personal information in a manner prohibited by law, please contact us. If we learn that we have collected personal information through the Service from a child without the consent of the child's parent or guardian as required by law, we will comply with applicable legal requirements to delete the information.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by updating the date of this Privacy Policy and posting it on the Site or other appropriate means. Any modifications to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon our posting the modified version (or as otherwise indicated at the time of posting). In all cases, your use of the Service after the effective date of any modified Privacy Policy indicates your acknowledging that the modified Privacy Policy applies to your interactions with the Service and our business.

### How to contact us

* Email: [\[email protected\]](https://ritual.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### State privacy rights notice

Except as otherwise provided, this section applies to residents of California, Virginia, and Colorado, and other states to the extent they have privacy laws in effect and applicable to us that grant their residents the rights described below, including the California Consumer Privacy Act ("**CCPA**"), the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act ("**CDPA**"), and the Colorado Privacy Act ("**CPA**") (collectively the "**State Privacy Laws**").

This section describes how we collect, use, and share Personal Information of residents of these states and the rights these users may have with respect to their Personal Information. Please note that not all rights listed below may be afforded to all users and that if you are not a resident of one of these states listed above, you may not be able to exercise these rights. In addition, **we may not be able to process your request if you do not provide us with sufficient detail to allow us to confirm your identity or understand and respond to it.**

For purposes of this section, the term "**Personal Information**" has the meaning given to "personal data", "personal information" or other similar terms in the State Privacy Laws and does not include information exempted from the scope of the State Privacy Laws. In some cases, we may provide a different privacy notice to certain categories of residents of these states, such as job applicants residing in California, in which case that notice will apply instead of this section.

**Your privacy rights**. The State Privacy Laws may provide residents with some or all of the rights listed below. and some State Privacy Laws do not provide these rights to their residents. Therefore, we may decline your request in certain cases as permitted by law.

* **Information**. You can request the following information about how we have collected and used your Personal Information during the past 12 months:
    
    * The categories of Personal Information that we have collected
        
    * The categories of sources from which we collected Personal Information
        
    * The business or commercial purpose for collecting and/or selling Personal Information
        
    * The categories of third parties with which we share Personal Information
        
    * The categories of Personal Information that we sold or disclosed for a business purpose
        
    * The categories of third parties to whom the Personal Information was sold or disclosed for a business purpose
        
* **Access**
    
    * You can request a copy of the Personal Information that we have collected about you during the past 12 months.
        
* **Appeal**
    
    * You can appeal our denial of any request validly submitted.
        
* **Correction**
    
    * You can ask us to correct inaccurate Personal Information that we have collected about you.
        
* **Deletion**
    
    * You can ask us to delete the Personal Information that we have collected from you.
        
* **Opt-out.**
    
    * **Opt-out of certain processing for targeted advertising purposes.**
        
        You can opt-out of certain processing of personal information for targeted advertising purposes.
        
    * **Opt-out of profiling/automated decision making.**
        
        You can opt-out of automated processing or profiling performed on personal information to evaluate, analyze, or predict personal aspects related to a person's economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behavior, location, or movements.
        
    * **Opt-out of other sales of personal data.**
        
        You can opt-out of other sales of your Personal Information.
        
* **Limit processing of Sensitive Personal Information.**
    
    * You can ask us to limit the processing of any Sensitive Personal Information we collect as necessary for our (1) Service delivery and operations, (2) Compliance and protection, (3) research and development, or (4) Service improvement and analytics purposes.
        
* **Nondiscrimination**
    
    * You are entitled to exercise the rights described above free from discrimination as prohibited by the State Privacy Laws.

**Exercising your right to information/know, access, appeal, correction, deletion, and limit processing of Sensitive Personal Information.** You may submit requests to exercise these rights online using our [privacy request form](https://preferences.ritual.com/privacy), or by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://ritual.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Exercising your right to opt-out of the "sale" or "sharing" of your Personal Information**. Like many companies, we use services that help deliver interest-based ads to you. The State Privacy Laws may classify our use of some of these services as "selling" or "sharing" your Personal Information to or with the advertising partners that provide the services. You can update your preferences to opt-out of tracking for targeted advertising purposes or other sales of Personal Information by clicking on the "Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information" link at the bottom of the site. California residents can also turn on the Global Privacy Control (GPC) to opt out of the "sale" of your personal information for each participating browser system that you use. Learn more at the [Global Privacy Control website](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).

**Verification of Identity; Authorized agents**. We may need to verify your identity in order to process your information/know, access, appeal, correction, deletion, or other requests and reserve the right to confirm your residency. To verify your identity, we may require government identification, a declaration under penalty of perjury, or other information, where permitted by law.

Under some State Privacy Laws, you may enable an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. However, we may need to verify your authorized agent's identity and authority to act on your behalf. We may require a copy of a valid power of attorney given to your authorized agent pursuant to applicable law. If you have not provided your agent with such a power of attorney, we may ask you to take additional steps permitted by law to verify that your request is authorized, such as by providing your agent with written and signed permission to exercise your State Privacy Laws rights on your behalf, the information we request to verify your identity, and confirmation that you have given the authorized agent permission to submit the request.

**Personal information that we collect, use, and disclose**. We have summarized the Personal Information we collect and may disclose to third parties by reference below to both the categories defined in the "Personal information we collect" section of this Policy above and the categories of Personal Information specified in the CCPA (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.140) and describes our practices currently and during the 12 months preceding the effective date of this Privacy Policy. Information you voluntarily provide to us, such as in free-form webforms, may contain other categories of personal information not described below.

**Statutory category: Identifiers (online)**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Profile data
        
    * Data about others
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Payment processors
        
    * Advertising partners
        
    * Third parties designated by you
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
    * Business and marketing partners
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * Advertising partners (to facilitate online advertising)
        
    * Business and marketing partners

**Statutory category: Identifiers (other)**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Profile data
        
    * Device data
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Payment processors
        
    * Advertising partners
        
    * Third parties designated by you
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
    * Business and marketing partners
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * Advertising partners (to facilitate online advertising)
        
    * Business and marketing partners

**Statutory category: California Customer Records (as defined in California Civil Code §1798.80)**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Transactional data
        
    * Data about others
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Payment processors
        
    * Advertising partners
        
    * Third parties designated by you
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
    * Business and marketing partners
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * Advertising partners (to facilitate online advertising)
        
    * Business and marketing partners

**Statutory category: Protected Classification Characteristics**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Pregnancy-related data
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Third parties designated by you
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * None

**Statutory category: Commercial information**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Transactional data
        
    * Marketing data
        
    * Online activity data
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Payment processors
        
    * Advertising partners
        
    * Third parties designated by you
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
    * Business and marketing partners
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * Advertising partners (to facilitate online advertising)
        
    * Business and marketing partners

**Statutory category: Financial Information**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Transactional data
        
    * Payment data
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * None

**Statutory category: Internet or Network Information**

* Personal Information ("PI") we collect in this category:
    
    * Marketing data
        
    * Device data
        
    * Online activity data
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Payment processors
        
    * Advertising partners
        
    * Third parties designated by you
        
    * Professional advisors
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
    * Business and marketing partners
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * Advertising partners (to facilitate online advertising)
        
    * Business and marketing partners

**Statutory category: Inferences**

* May be derived from:
    
    * Contact data
        
    * Profile data
        
    * Transactional data
        
    * Marketing data
        
    * Device data
        
    * Online activity data
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we disclose PI for a business purpose:
    
    * Affiliates
        
    * Service providers
        
    * Advertising partners
        
    * Authorities and others
        
    * Business transferees
        
    * Business and marketing partners
        
* Categories of third parties to whom we "sell" or "share" PI:
    
    * Advertising partners (to facilitate online advertising)
        
    * Business and marketing partners

**Shine the light law**. California residents may send us requests to [\[email protected\]](https://ritual.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for identification of third parties to whom we have disclosed your personal information during the preceding calendar year for such third parties' direct-marketing purposes. In your request, you must include the statement "Shine the Light Request," and provide your first and last name and mailing address and certify that you are a California resident. We reserve the right to require additional information to confirm your identity and California residency. Please note that we will not accept requests via telephone, mail, or facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

### Notice to UK users

The information provided in this Notice to UK users applies only to individuals in the UK.

**Controller**. Natals, Inc. (d/b/a Ritual) is the controller in respect of the processing of your personal information covered by this Privacy Policy for the purposes of the so-called **"UK GDPR"** (i.e., the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 as it forms part of UK law post-Brexit). See the Contact Us section above for contact details.

**Our UK GDPR Representatives**. Our representative in the UK appointed under the UK GDPR is:

Email: [\[email protected\]](https://ritual.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Post: GDPR Local Ltd

1st Floor Front Suite 27-29

North Street, Brighton England BN1 1EB

**Personal Data**.

* For UK users, references to your "personal information" in this Privacy Policy should be understood to include a reference to your "personal data" (as defined in the UK GDPR).
    
* So, what is "personal data"? – essentially, personal data is information about an individual, from which that individual is either directly identified or can be identified.
    
* It does **not** include 'anonymous data' (i.e., information where the identity of the relevant individual has been permanently removed and that individual is no longer identified or identifiable).

**Legal bases for processing**. In respect of each of the purposes for which we use your personal information, the UK GDPR requires us to ensure that we have a "legal basis" for that use. Our legal bases for processing your personal information described in this Privacy Policy are listed below.

* Where we need to perform a contract, we are about to enter into or have entered into with you ("**Contractual Necessity**").
    
* Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests ("**Legitimate Interests**"). More detail about the specific legitimate interests pursued in respect of each purpose we use your personal information for is set out in the list below.
    
* Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation ("**Compliance with Law**").
    
* Where we have your specific consent to carry out the processing for the purpose in question ("**Consent**").

In addition, for any special categories of personal data we process (e.g., data related to your health, such as pregnancy-related data), we also have to establish a condition to processing such data, because it is considered to be more sensitive in nature – for example, we may look to obtain your explicit consent to the Processing of those special categories of personal data for one or more specified purposes ("**Explicit Consent**").

We have set out below, in a list format, the legal bases we rely on in respect of the relevant Purposes for which we use your personal information – for more information on these Purposes, what they cover, and the data types involved, see How we use your personal information.

**Purpose: Service delivery**

* Contractual Necessity

**Purpose: Security**

* Compliance with Law
    
* Legitimate Interests. We have a legitimate interest in ensuring the ongoing security and proper operation of our Site, our Services and associated IT services, systems and networks.

**Purpose: Service personalization**

* Legitimate Interests. We have a legitimate interest in providing you with a good service, which is personalized to you and that remembers your selections and preferences.
    
* Consent, in respect of any optional cookies used for this purpose
    
* For any special categories of personal data (e.g., data related to your health, such as pregnancy-related data): Explicit Consent

**Purpose: Direct marketing**

* Legitimate Interests. We have a legitimate interest in promoting our operations and goals as an organization and sending marketing communications for that purpose.
    
* Consent, in circumstances or in jurisdictions where consent is required under applicable data protection laws to the sending of any given marketing communications
    
* For any special categories of personal data (e.g., data related to your health, such as pregnancy-related data): Explicit Consent

**Purpose: Interest-based advertising**

* Consent
    
* Legitimate Interests. We have a legitimate interest in personalizing the advertisements served to you and evaluating the use of our website.

**Purpose: Promotions and contests**

* Contractual Necessity to administer the promotions and contests in accordance with the terms or rules thereof (including communicating with you as and where necessary)
    
* In respect of promoting these promotions and contests:
    
    * Legitimate Interests. We have a legitimate interest in promoting these promotions and contests, including associated publicising of our business and operations.
        
    * Consent – in circumstances or in jurisdictions where consent is required under applicable data protection laws to the sending of any given promotional communications.

**Purpose: Service analytics**

* Consent

**Purpose: Data sharing in the context of corporate events**

* Legitimate interest. We and any relevant third parties have a legitimate interest in providing information to relevant third parties who are involved in an actual or prospective corporate event (including to enable them to investigate – and, where relevant, to continue to operate – all or relevant part(s) of our operations). However, we would always look to take steps to minimize the amount and sensitivity of any personal information shared in these contexts where possible and appropriate.

**Purpose: Compliance with law and co-operation with authorities**

* Compliance with Law.
    
* Legitimate interest. Where Compliance with Law is not applicable, we and any relevant third parties have a legitimate interest in participating in, supporting and following legal process and requests, including through co operation with authorities.
    
* For any special categories of personal data (e.g., data related to your health, such as pregnancy-related data): The processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

**Purpose: Protection and enforcement of rights**

* Compliance with Law.
    
* Legitimate interest. We and any relevant third parties have a legitimate interest of ensuring the protection, maintenance and enforcement of our and their rights, property, and/or safety.
    
* For any special categories of personal data (e.g., data related to your health, such as pregnancy-related data): The processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

**Purpose: To create aggregated, de-identified and/or anonymized data**

* Legitimate interest. We have legitimate interest, and believe it is also in your interests, that we are able to take steps to ensure that our Services and how we use Personal Information is as un-privacy intrusive as possible.

**Purpose: Further uses**

* The original legal basis relied upon, if the relevant further use is compatible with the initial purpose for which the Personal Information was collected.
    
* Consent, if the relevant further use is not compatible with the initial purpose for which the personal information was collected.

**Special Categories of Personal Data**. As noted above, you may choose to provide us with your pregnancy-related data. We will only collect such data where you have provided us with your explicit consent to its use for the specific purpose of personalizing your experience. If you do not want us to process your pregnancy-status data, you can always choose not to do so by selecting 'Prefer not to say'.

We will not use your personal information (whether it is directly special category personal data or not) to create inferences or to otherwise reveal information concerning your health / health conditions, your genetic information, your racial or ethnic origin, your sex life or sexual orientation or any other special category(ies) of personal data without your explicit consent. If you do not provide your explicit consent, we will not carry out any Processing that is designed or intended to treat you differently on the basis of a possible inference or 'educated guess' that we could theoretically make about, or that could deduce, these types of special categories (e.g., from your purchase history).

**Retention**

We retain personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collected it, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements, to establish or defend legal claims, or for fraud prevention purposes.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

When we no longer require the personal information we have collected about you, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. If we anonymize your personal information (so that it can no longer be associated with you), we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**Your rights**

The UK GDPR gives you certain rights regarding your personal information in certain circumstances. If you are located in the UK, you may ask us to take the following actions in relation to your personal information that we hold:

* **Access**. Provide you with information about our processing of your personal information and give you access to your personal information.
    
* **Correct**. Update or correct inaccuracies in your personal information.
    
* **Delete**. Delete your personal information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it – you also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal information where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).
    
* **Transfer**. Transfer a machine-readable copy of your personal information to you or a third party of your choice.
    
* **Restrict**. Restrict the processing of your personal information, for example if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it.
    
* **Object**. Object to our processing of your personal information where we are relying on Legitimate Interests – you also have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes.
    
* **Opt-out**. Stop sending you direct marketing communications. You may continue to receive service-related and other non-marketing emails.
    
* **Consent withdrawal**. Where we rely on your consent and/or explicit consent to process your personal information you may withdraw that consent at any time.

You may submit these requests online using our [privacy request form](https://preferences.ritual.com/privacy), or by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://ritual.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and process your request.

Applicable law may require or permit us to decline your request. If we decline your request, we will tell you why, subject to legal restrictions. If you would like to submit a complaint about our use of your personal information or our response to your requests regarding your personal information, you may contact us or submit a complaint to the UK data protection regulator:

The Information Commissioner's Office

Water Lane, Wycliffe House

Wilmslow - Cheshire SK9 5AF

Tel. +44 303 123 1113

Website: [https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/)

**Data transfers outside the UK**.

We are a U.S.-based company and many of our service providers, advisers, partners or other recipients of data are also based in the U.S. This means that, if you use the Service, your personal data will necessarily be accessed and processed in the U.S. It may also be provided to recipients in other countries outside the UK.

It is important to note that that the U.S. is not the subject of an 'adequacy decision' under the UK GDPR – basically, this means that the U.S. legal regime is not considered by the UK government to provide an adequate level of protection for personal information, which is equivalent to that provided by relevant UK laws.

Where we share your personal data with third parties who are based outside the UK, we try to ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by making sure one of the following mechanisms is implemented:

* **Transfers to territories with an adequacy decision**. We may transfer your personal information to countries or territories whose laws have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the UK Government (from time to time).
    
* **Transfers to territories without an adequacy decision**.
    
* We may transfer your personal information to countries or territories whose laws have **not** been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for Personal Data by the UK Government (e.g., the U.S., see above).
    
* However, in these cases:
    
* we may use specific appropriate safeguards approved by the UK Information Commissioner's Office or UK Government, which are designed to give personal information the same protection it has in the UK – for example, requiring the recipient of personal information to enter into the relevant form of the so-called 'International Data Transfer Agreement' issued or approved from time to time; or
    
* in limited circumstances, we may rely on an exception, or 'derogation', which permits us to transfer your information to such country despite the absence of an 'adequacy decision' or 'appropriate safeguards' – for example, reliance on your explicit consent to that transfer.

You may contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal information out of the UK.

### Notice to Canadian residents

If you are a resident of Canada, this section applies to you. You have the right to request access to the personal information we hold about you, and to have information that is inaccurate or incomplete updated. We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and your right to access, and to provide you with the personal information that we hold about you. Applicable law may allow or require us to refuse to provide you with access to some or all of the personal information that we hold about you, or we may have destroyed, erased, or made your personal information anonymous in accordance with our record retention obligations and practices. If we cannot provide you with access to your personal information, we will inform you of the reasons why, subject to any legal or regulatory restrictions.

Except as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulation, we will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. Under some circumstances we may anonymize your personal information so that it can no longer be associated with you. We reserve the right to use such anonymous and de-identified data for any legitimate business purpose without further notice to you or your consent.

Footer
------

### We have high standards for emails too.

Email

Subscribe

### Shop

### Shop

### About

### About

### More

### More

[Terms of Service](https://ritual.com/terms-of-service)[Privacy Policy](https://ritual.com/privacy-policy)[CA Transparency Act](https://ritual.com/articles/protecting-people-supply-chain)Accessibility

Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information

© 2024 Ritual. All rights reserved.

Footnotes
---------

\* These statements have not been evaluated by the Food and Drug Administration. This product is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease [⏎](#footnote-ref)

The FDA plays a specific role in regulating the nutraceutical industry. [Learn More](https://ritual.com/articles/the-fdas-role-in-the-supplement-industry "Read more about the FDAs role in the supplement industry.").

Your Cart
=========

Loading...

Subtotal

$0.00

Shipping

Free

Continue to Checkout
